In Toronto's war
on crime.
the worst offenders
are pursued by the detectives
of the Specialized Criminal
Investigations Unit.
These are their stories.
- Come on. Ivy.
Stay for one more song.
No. Amy.
Uh. seriously. I have to go.
I have class tomorrow at nine.
- You're literally
acing every course.
you can take a morning off.
What? Is something wrong?
Is-is it Rob?
- No. I'm fine.
Go sing. I'll see you at home.
Go!
Go.
Okay.
- Uh. can I close my tab?
- Sure.
No whole lotta love tonight?
- What?
- Nothing.
Here.
- Rob. stop calling.
I'm not at Tempo.
- Ivy. if you're still
feeling this way.
maybe you should take a break.
Go see your parents.
- So you think I should just
run away from my problems?
- No. I think you need
to manage your stress.
- But you don't think
this is real. do you?
Like. I'm not living in some
fantasy world. Dr. Nielson!
- I didn't say that. Ivy.
Come. Sit.
Please.
I think you should consider
doing what's best for you
in this situation.
- I know what's best for me.
And I'm not going anywhere.
- Everyone's looking at this
all wrong.
I've done the test.
These wounds were made by
something easily accessible.
Um. a steak knife.
A pairing knife.
- So. you think the killer was
in the house with her.
Followed her out?
- Why? Is that what you think?
Come on.
Please. Ivy. Help me out.
Why would someone stab
this woman seven times?
Passion makes people do
irrational things. Morris.
And you'd know that
if you didn't spend all
your time playing with knives.
- Okay. so what is it then?
I wanna possess you.
be you. so...
I'm gonna kill you?
- Hello?
Uh. yes. yes.
Thank you for calling back.
Uh. yeah. I can be there.
- Is that your.
uh. mystery lead?
- Uh. you're sure
that's what you heard?
- Yes. I'm certain.
- Who else have you told
about this?
- You're the first.
- Rob. what the hell
are you doing?
I just...
wanna talk.
Been avoiding me.
- We've talked for months.
You don't listen.
We broke up.
- Okay. but...
what if I didn't want to?
- Hey. it's me.
Great work.
I just think that maybe...
our last chapter needs
a bit more muscle.
I mean. I know you're all about
the subtlety and that's awesome.
but I think that
if we're gonna make waves.
we need to hit it harder.
That's my thought.
Anyway. I'll see you soon.
- Amy? Are you home?
I need to talk to you.
Amy?
Amy. I'm on my way to campus
to find you.
Call me as soon as you--
Hello? Campus Services.
What's your emergency?
Hello?
- Campus Security got a call
from this phone at 11:22.
but there was nobody
on the line.
They sent somebody at 11:30.
thinking it was a prank.
- No such luck.
- Yeah.
- Ivy Abbott. 20 years old.
Dean says she's a third-year
Criminology Major.
She's got a 4.0 GPA.
- Smart kid.
- You talked to the parents yet?
- Yeah. They're both academics.
They're in Edinburg for a year.
they're flying back today.
Ivy was their only kid.
So...
what sent Ivy Abbott
to an emergency phone
in the middle of the night?
- Well. her cell phone died.
- Uh... here.
See if it'll charge.
- Oh. great. Thanks.
- I wonder if someone
was following her.
- Well. these indentations
between her fingers.
Could be she tried
to arm herself?
- Maybe with her keys
for protection.
Okay. so. she runs to the phone
to call for help.
but the killer
stabs her in the neck
and then drags her
and flips her over.
Keeps stabbing.
The wound to her neck
would've been fatal.
The six stabs on her back.
that was anger.
This was personal.
You found a weapon?
- Uh. no. Nothing yet.
- Anything on her person that
could account for this?
Looks like rope burn.
- No. we just found her wallet.
keys. and her phone.
Oh. it's charged.
Thanks.
Hey.
"What do you mean you're too
scared to stay home. Call me."
Ivy said she was
coming back to our apartment.
I was studying on campus
till midnight.
My phone was on Do Not Disturb.
And when I got
Ivy's voicemail...
...I texted her
and she didn't respond.
I ran home. then I found this.
I tried to blow them all out.
but there are so many.
- Amy. is there anyone
we can call?
Can I text my mom?
- Of course.
Amy. has anything like this
happened before?
- The first time there were just
a couple of candles.
Then a few more.
It's the third time.
I've never
been so scared.
- Do you have any idea
who might have done this?
- Yeah. I figured it was Rob.
Ivy's ex.
I-it started a couple months ago
when they broke up.
- Did Ivy ever inform
the police?
- Yeah. she tried.
The cop at the station
said that it's not a crime
to leave something outside
of someone's house.
- Yeah... Sweetheart.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Do you think this was some grand
gesture to try to get Ivy back?
- We tried every other way.
Constant calling. texting.
Guy's unhinged.
- What. you think
I did something to Ivy?
No. no. I would never hurt her.
- Well. what do
you know about this. huh?
It's got quite
the distinctive scent.
Cedar. cannabis.
Canadian wildflowers.
And a hundred of these
were left on
Ivy's patio last night.
- That's crazy.
- Where were you
last night. Rob?
- I was at the Madison.
Got there at. like. 10 PM
with a few buddies.
We stayed until.
I don't know. 1:30?
Get back here with Kailey.
She just left.
- Kailey?
- I'm trying to see new people.
Get over Ivy.
Best six months of my life
were with her.
- So why did you break up?
I don't know. I...
She just pulled away.
She broke up with me.
She wouldn't tell me why.
She...
She shut down her social media.
started to go to therapy.
which I thought was weird.
I mean. she never wanted to talk
about her feelings before.
- Who's her therapist?
- Someone on campus.
Sarah something.
- Ivy and I met four times
in the last few months.
She was a great student.
Good kid.
- Yeah. she needed
someone to talk to.
- Yes. She was stressed.
Anxious.
- Did this anxiety have anything
to do with. uh.
unwanted attention?
- A lot of female students
seek out guidance
regarding harassment.
Detective. and unfortunately
Ivy was no different.
Look. I... I wouldn't normally
do this. but. um.
You can have my notes.
They might help.
- Thank you.
- Ivy was convinced that
someone was following her.
She said that they left things
outside of her apartment.
lurked near her place.
To be honest. I couldn't tell
whether this was real
or whether
it was some delusion
brought on by
some underlying issue.
- It says here. "Possible BPD"
I'm assuming that's Borderline
Personality Disorder?
Disordered sense of self.
intense emotions...
- Relationship instability. Yes.
All motivated by
a fear of abandonment.
But I wasn't sure because Ivy
also exhibited traits
of Paranoid Personality
Disorder.
Delusions. distrust.
- And you never made
an official diagnosis?
- No. no. and...
Considering what happened to
her. I suppose I...
I got that all wrong.
Regardless. it would take
me more than
four sessions to be sure.
You know.
some folks go after
this stuff with a hammer.
I paint in watercolour.
You know. it takes time.
Patience.
I wanted to help Ivy.
I really did.
but I couldn't report
the harassment for her.
- Did Ivy ever describe
this person?
- The only thing that
I remember her saying
is that he wore
an army jacket.
- It's so sad. isn't it?
Did you know her?
She was
my girlfriend.
- Oh. my God...
I'm so sorry.
- Apparently.
she tried to report it.
but the description
of the guy was vague
and you know what
they say about stalking.
Yes. homicide in slow motion.
Finished Ivy Abbott's autopsy.
The killer twisted
the knife inside her neck
almost 180 degrees.
- He sliced her carotid
and her jugular?
Yeah. She bled out quickly.
I looked into those abrasions
on her left hand.
there's thin fibres embedded.
I sent them for testing.
- Possibly clutching
onto an object as a weapon
when the keys failed?
- Maybe.
I once tried to fend off a
subway perv using a debit card.
- Yeah. I pretended ChapStick
was pepper-spray.
It actually worked.
Her killer wasn't a stranger.
He had a personal
connection with her.
- Yeah. he either hated her
or desired her.
- Maybe he even felt
a whole lotta love.
It's the name of the candle.
Forensics just came back.
pinpointed a proprietary blend
of cedar. cannabis.
and Canadian wildflowers.
Created by a Canadian company.
Shy Wolf.
I called them and guess
who bought 150 candles
using their credit card online?
Hope you have a reservation
'cause we're totally
booked tonight.
- Oh. I'm sure you can squeeze
us in for. I don't know.
five minutes and 33 seconds?
- Well. that's just enough time
to do a hearty rendition
of Whole Lotta Love.
- Carter Harold. right?
That's you?
- Yeah.
- Well. seems recently
you bought
a whole lotta
these candles.
- It's very expensive
to just leave them all
in Ivy Abbott's
backyard.
- Come on. Carter.
That's enough.
- I didn't kill Ivy. I swear.
- You sure?
'Cause you were stalking her.
- Okay. I left the candles on
the night she died.
On all those nights.
But I just wanted...
- Wanted what?
Be her own personal boogeyman?
- No. I wanted her to know
that I cared about her.
The candles.
They were a message.
They were named after a song
we sang together.
- You're telling me
a 20-year-old
sang Led Zeppelin
at karaoke?
- Not exactly. Um...
I was in a room
on my own one night.
But then I heard a voice
in the hall joining in.
I logged out and saw...
...her.
- Then you got hooked.
Pulled her address off her ID.
went to her house.
started taking photos.
lighting candles.
- She needed to know how I felt.
What about how she felt?
'Cause I'm pretty sure
you terrified her.
Every. Single. Time.
- See. I-I'm. uh. pretty new to
this. so forgive me.
but you want us to believe you
trespassed onto her property.
peaked through her windows
and took some pretty
intrusive photos of her.
but then you didn't follow her
to a deserted area.
stab her in the neck
and in the back?
Carter. what did Ivy do
when she saw the candles?
Answer the question.
- She ran away. Okay?
She obviously didn't like them.
- Shocker.
- So I left and I went to work
a late shift at the bar.
Check the cameras.
I was there by 11:15.
- We will.
- Honestly. I wished
I followed her.
I could've helped her.
- Well. maybe it's not
too late to help.
I mean. you followed
her around. right?
- Yeah.
- What was she up to?
- She was spending
way too much time
at that Criminology building.
- She had classes there.
- No. it's not just class.
It's...
...something else.
Every day. she goes
to some weird locked room
that only a few
people had a key to.
- What's inside?
- I don't know.
but I think it's bad for her.
Very bad.
- Let me know when you're done.
- That looks like a bunch of
true crime nerds made a nest.
- Or the Cold Case Club.
They do seminars supervised
by Professor Garrett Poole.
- What's the case?
- The victim was
Kat Berman. murdered in 2019.
Student at Queens University.
She was stabbed
once in the neck.
- And six times... in the back.
Exactly like Ivy.
- So Ivy Abbott was studying
Kat Berman's murder
and ends up getting killed
in exactly the same way?
- Yeah. down to the twist
of the knife.
Uh. take a look at Ivy's autopsy
and Kat's autopsy
from six years ago.
Their fatal neck wounds
were caused
by the exact
same maneuver.
- Followed by six stabs
to the back.
The only difference
was the marks on the hand.
Ivy had them. Kat did not.
You talk to Kingston PD?
- Yeah. they gave us
access to Kat's file.
but they haven't had
a new lead in forever.
- So. now we have
two dead students.
similar ages.
same wound.
Yeah. We might be
looking at a serial murderer.
- Or a copycat who knew
the wound pattern well.
Maybe because they studied it
at Cold Case Club.
- Ivy was an excellent student.
- I'm sorry for your loss.
Professor Poole.
Uh. profile told us she was
in your Cold Case Club?
- Yeah. one of only
10 kids selected.
- Yes. it was an invitation only
criminology seminar
for third-year students
and Ivy was. yeah. she was
doing incredibly well.
They all were.
- So you thought
your best and brightest
could solve
Kat Berman's murder?
Uh. stump the Kingston PD?
- No. it's more of
a teaching exercise.
- Hmm.
- So you take an unsolvable case
and give it to a bunch
of smart kids.
- And see what they do with it.
Each bring their own expertise.
their own point of view.
It's fascinating.
- Hmm.
- And what was. uh. Ivy's angle?
- Interpreting witness
testimony.
- Hmm.
And what if. uh. a student
discovers a lead?
- Well. then I would take it
to the cold case unit.
but I've been using this one
for a couple years now
and so far there are
no new leads.
- Hmm.
But. uh. Ivy wanted
to find one. Yeah.
Uh. we heard she spent
quite a lot of time
in the seminar room
after hours.
- Yes. they all did.
I told them they'd get top marks
if they solved it
and they couldn't take
the files home.
- Did those files include. uh.
Kat Berman's autopsy?
- Yes. Why?
- Oh. we were wondering if any
of the students were. uh.
taking the pathology angle?
- Cause of death. Injuries.
- Yes. Morris Lemay.
He's an aspiring
forensic pathologist.
He was trying to recreate
Kat Berman's wounds
using various unique methods.
- Many body pathologists
practise replicating
knife wounds.
It's not weird.
- So. does everyone work
on Miss Piggy?
- Well. they should.
The consistency of pig flesh
is very close to human.
- Well. funny.
That's why we're here.
Morris. where were you
the night Ivy died?
- I didn't kill Ivy.
I was with my parents. Here.
All night.
You can ask them.
- What's on your mind?
- If only I'd move faster.
Done better.
Could've found out who really
did this and...
Ivy would still be alive.
- Do you think Kat's killer
murdered Ivy?
- Isn't it obvious?
Ivy probably figured out
who did it.
You call yourself
a detective...
- Professor Poole says that
there were no new leads.
- Yeah. well. Professor Poole
doesn't know everything.
Ivy finished reviewing
witness testimony
and moved on to something that
wasn't even assigned to her.
Something that no one
was allowed to do.
- Interviewing real witnesses.
- How'd you know?
- Oh. well. that's exactly
what he would've done.
So. what was Ivy's strategy?
- Ivy was really
into victimology.
In particular.
victim facilitation.
You know. the theory of what
makes someone a target.
But nothing of
the witness testimony
made it seem like Kat
was a high-risk victim.
Just went to work and to school.
- So Ivy wanted to know how the
killer came into Kat's orbit.
- Yeah. Ivy figured the perp was
either an unassuming random.
a stalker--
- Or someone Kat didn't want
anyone else to know about.
Did Ivy find any new leads?
- She went to meet a witness
the day she died.
I saw the address she wrote down
before she left.
- Yes. Ivy Abbott came
by here at 6 PM.
We chatted. she left.
I was here till 12.
I didn't even know her.
- But Ivy thought that
you might know Kat Berman.
- And where was this?
- Six years ago. I was living
in Kingston with my aunt and
on the weekend I delivered
pizzas for a place
called Max Dough.
- And Ivy knew you were
delivering pizzas to Kat?
- She saw a photo of our pizza
box in Kat's recycling.
Part of the case files. I guess.
- And Ivy wanted to know
if you ever saw anyone
with Kat on the weekends?
- Yes. And there was a guy there
with her sometimes.
Definitely a boyfriend.
- So Damien.
did you ever. uh. see a face.
get a name?
No. but I heard his voice.
He was annoying.
Told the same story
over and over.
So our pizza box was red. right?
Every time Kat took it inside.
he would make a comment
on how it was
the exact same colour of his
fancy cottage in Newfoundland.
So when I told Ivy about it.
she got really tense.
Said she needed to talk to her
professor right away.
- Hmm. Funny.
He didn't tell us that.
- Morris.
What are you doing here?
- I. uh. came to grab
some of my research.
- Well. you won't need it.
Out of respect for Ivy.
I'm cancelling
this seminar for good.
But what about
our grades?
- Is that all you can think
about? Your grades?
What kind of
question is that. man?
What's wrong with you?
- Uh...
Uh. I'm sorry. You're right.
- Hang on. hang on.
I'm sorry. It's. um...
Marks are gonna be determined
based on the work
that's already been submitted.
You're okay. Don't worry.
- So you've never heard of
Damien Aku.
- No. Ivy never mentioned
meeting anyone named.
Damien Aku and...
I would never condone reaching
out to a stranger
about the cold case.
- Really?
'Cause Damien told us
that Ivy's first priority
was to report back to you
about a new suspect.
- Well. she may have
sent an email.
Maybe it ended up
in my junk box.
I don't know.
my inbox is a mess.
I haven't had time
to go through--
- Sorry. this is the first
new clue in years
and you haven't
had time?
- I'm saying I didn't know
there was a new clue.
- Oh. okay.
Well. that's all right.
You know what.
we can fill you in.
Uh. so Ivy found out that
Kat had a secret boyfriend.
Now. we don't know his name.
- Oh. but we do know
that he owns some
pretty stunning property.
- Yeah. a red cottage
in Newfoundland.
- Kinda like this one.
- Were you dating Kat Berman.
Professor Poole?
- And what did you do
when Ivy found out?
We know he took a sabbatical
from Osler in 2019.
moved to Kingston to write
a book on the penitentiary.
Same year Kat was killed.
- Yeah. Kat worked in a library
that housed some of
the penitentiary archives.
They might have met there.
We haven't confirmed it.
but after Kat was killed.
Garrett Poole went back home
and eventually started
the Cold Case Club.
- It's possible he was simply
interested in the case.
They lived in the same city.
Maybe he read about it
in the newspaper--
- Yes. but now we're thinking
that he was sleeping with Kat.
So. he's either obsessed
with the woman he loved...
- Or he's a. uh. murdering
narcissist who's
spent the last three years
daring his students
to catch him.
- Who the hell
are we dealing with?
- We're about to find out.
- Yes. I was sleeping with
Kat Berman in 2019.
Our relationship has nothing
to do with her murder.
I didn't kill her.
I loved her.
- You used her murder as fodder
for a university class.
- I wanna solve the case.
- So did Ivy.
And from the looks of it.
she got dangerously close
to the truth.
Uh. we got a warrant to search
your communication
and. oh. you weren't lying about
your inbox being a mess.
But. uh. we found this
in your trash.
- What is this. uh. Ivy's email?
The one that.
uh. you couldn't find.
- Hmm.
- It was sent
the night she was killed.
but forgive me.
I-I left my glasses on my desk.
Perhaps you could
read it out to us.
- "I know you were dating Kat."
This isn't what this looks like.
Come on.
- No? Because you deleted
a very clear message from Ivy
that would give you a very clear
motive for murder.
- And let's face it. it might be
easier just to get rid of her
than to. uh.
have to track down and destroy
2.000 copies of a book with
a very damning detail on it.
- I did not kill Ivy out of some
kind of self-preservation
because I did not kill Kat.
Do you understand?
- Then why would you lie to us?
- Do you have any idea
how hard it is
to be a male professor
these days?
I did not want the fact that
I slept with Kat to get out.
Okay? It's not because
I killed her.
it's because I would be
ruined. I'd be cancelled.
I would lose everything.
Yeah. but Ivy
still knew.
Go after her?
- Yeah. your office is very.
very close to where
she was killed.
- Yeah. but I wasn't
at my office.
- Where were you?
- I was with a colleague
at her office.
- Who?
- Sarah Nielson.
I'm working with her
on my new book.
I was with her from 9:30
to midnight.
- Sarah Nielson
the campus therapist?
- Did you know that. um.
Sarah was treating Ivy?
I mean...
Yes.
- How?
- 'Cause I introduced them.
- Do you hand pick
all your students' therapists?
- Maybe you got your pal
to talk to Ivy
for the same reason
you trashed that email.
Because you didn't want
the world to know
that you and Ivy were also
in a sexual relationship.
- Yeah. that would make you
two for two.
That's two relationships.
two students.
Both dead.
- Ivy never told me
that she and Garrett Poole
were sleeping together.
I'd have to report that.
- Even though you're friends?
- I think that outweighs
friendships. Detective.
So do morals.
- And the night Ivy was killed?
- Well. Garrett was with me
in my office
till well
after midnight.
We were working on his new book.
Whatever was happening with Ivy.
Garrett's telling
the truth about that night.
- That's helpful. Sarah.
Thank you.
- Did forensics come back
on those fibres in Ivy's hand?
- I was just about to call you.
They're from a cord used
in retractable key card fobs.
- What. like the one Poole used
to let us into his office?
- It looked long enough
to wrap around Ivy's hand.
cause rope burn.
I knew we shouldn't have
let him go.
- No. the man had an alibi.
it was verified.
- But if you find the cord.
I can test it for Ivy's DNA.
- Thanks. Lucy. Standby.
Okay. you two. We need to be
very strategic here
because whether or not there's
DNA on that cord...
- Poole's alibi still stands.
- However. in my experience.
even the most
bulletproof
of alibis will weaken
when faced with a fear
of obstructing justice.
- So if we tell
ethical. moral Sarah
that we've got
some evidence against Poole.
she might bend.
- And if you gild the lily
by showing her a little more
of the horror of the crime
she's covering up...
- Hmm. she might break.
Can you. uh.
put a SPIN team on Poole?
- Nothing I'd rather do.
Go break that alibi.
Garrett.
Thank God they released you.
You okay?
- Yeah. I'm fine. I'm fine.
Thanks for talking to the cops.
You're a lifesaver.
- Um...
Garrett.
- Yeah?
- Is there anything
that you wanna tell me?
- About what?
- About Ivy?
Garrett.
I just lied
for you.
- Hey.
You know I didn't hurt her.
Right?
You know that.
Of course
you didn't!
But... I--
- But nothing.
Why should we give
some myopic cop
anyone who have opportunity
to pin this on me?
I left your office. I was out
walking around the campus.
Ju-just processing all
these great ideas that you had
for the last chapter. you know?
You're amazing.
you know that. right?
- Oh. stop.
- God. I'm so lucky to have you.
- What do you mean?
I mean...
you're loyal and you're...
You're faithful and you're...
you're so smart.
It's just pure.
There's no silliness.
There's no messy feelings
getting in the way.
- Why are you showing me these?
- Because we believe your friend
Garrett Poole
did that to Ivy Abbott.
- That's-that's impossible.
I told you
that we were together.
- It's amazing what people
will do to protect a friend.
What do you have in your pocket?
Come on. show me.
Okay. so you're by yourself.
It's nighttime.
Someone's following you.
Out of all of this. what do
you use to defend yourself?
So they have a knife.
You have a pen.
- I mean. compared to you
right now.
Ivy was lucky.
She had her keys on her.
Intertwined them between
her fingers
in the hope that she could
take a swing and then run.
But she didn't.
'Cause someone stabbed her
in the side of the neck
before she got the chance.
Why would Garrett
do this?
- Well. Ivy learned that
there was another student
he was involved with who
also wound up dead.
Kat Berman. six years ago.
- There were more?
I knew about Ivy.
- Wait. You knew that Poole
was sleeping with Ivy?
Why are you wasting our time?
- Okay.
Ivy told me.
I was horrified. but I couldn't
always trust what she said.
I told her
it wasn't appropriate
and she told me that she was
too scared to break up with him.
Now I could never imagine
Garrett threatening a woman.
- Well. this looks more
than a threat. doesn't it?
- Garrett wouldn't--
- Hurt anyone?
Come on. Sarah.
Predators don't just
hide in the shadows.
They're in nice offices
in nice homes.
in positions of power.
- And you are enabling him.
Why?
- I didn't want Garrett
to be ruined.
What if Garrett was telling the
truth? What if Ivy was lying?
- But she wasn't.
So don't lie for him.
- Garrett was in my office
with my until 11 PM.
I'm sorry.
I never thought that he could
do something like this.
so when he asked me to say that
we were together until midnight.
I said okay.
- Detectives. a word.
SPIN team just called.
Poole is on the move.
he's got a suitcase with him.
I'll deal with Sarah. you go.
- There he is.
We need his key fob.
- Doctor Poole.
- Garrett Poole.
Police. Stop!
- What the hell
is going on here?
I didn't do anything.
- We'll see about that.
- Garrett Poole.
you're under arrest
for the murder
of Ivy Abbott.
- I was headed to Union Station.
I'm catching a train to go to
Hudson Valley to see a friend.
I'm not guilty of anything.
- Well. the jury's out on that.
but we'll have a clearer picture
once forensics comes back
with the key fob.
You see. we believe
it was the last thing that
Ivy Abbott grabbed for
before she died.
- You knew it was
only a matter of time
before Ivy outed you
as Kat's killer.
so you got rid of her
to save yourself!
I didn't kill Ivy!
I didn't kill Kat.
I told you. I love them.
Both of them!
- You preyed on two
young students
and both have ended up dead.
- Is that the results?
The DNA test?
What does it say?
- Negative for Ivy's DNA.
- Yeah. I told you!
I told you I didn't kill anyone!
- Then why did you
ask a colleague
to fabricate
an alibi for you?
- I didn't ask her to do that.
It was her idea.
- So. she just came up with this
whole plan all by herself.
Why?
- Sarah is a friend.
Okay? She's a close friend.
She adores me.
She'd do anything for me.
So when we found out
that Ivy was killed.
a student we both knew.
Sarah suggested that we just say
we were together.
You know?
Just to keep things tidy.
So one more time.
Where were you?
- At 11 o'clock.
I went out for a walk.
And Sarah stayed behind
and worked on my edits.
Leaving you both alone
and unaccounted for at the time
of Ivy Abbott's murder.
Let's get Sarah's
interview up.
- Yeah. I'm on it.
What do you have
in your pockets?
Come on. show me.
Hmm. okay. so.
You're alone. It's nighttime.
- The white key card.
It's not the official blue one
the rest of the staff have.
It's temporary.
- And she tried to hide it.
Which mean she got
rid of her official card
and the fob
that went with it.
- And as Poole said.
"She adores him.
She'd do anything to help him."
- Sarah Nielson
was inside Ivy's head.
- Yeah. she knew
she could kill Ivy
and point the finger at any
number of people in Ivy's life.
- Even pointed you two
toward a stalker.
- And all the while.
she was covering for Poole.
which also gave herself
an alibi.
- That's some fancy footwork.
- Hmm.
- But then for some reason.
she decided to throw Poole
under the bus. Why?
- Oh. 'cause we offered him up
as a patsy.
And if Sarah's smart. uh.
the only piece of hard evidence
that we hoped to test
is long gone.
- Finding that fob
wouldn't help.
I'm Sarah's defence lawyer.
First thing I'd say.
everyone at Osler has that fob.
30.000 people could be
your killer.
your client has no alibi.
- She was in her office.
Working.
- The therapists' offices don't
have cameras. I checked.
- Thank you. Counselor.
but I have the floor.
- Oh.
- Hmm.
- You don't have my client's
prints on the murder weapon
because you don't have
a murder weapon.
No sign of her on CCTV.
At least not a
recognizable Sarah.
- Okay. but what is
a recognizable Sarah?
The woman is a cypher.
I-I don't think I've seen
the real Sarah this entire time.
- This... This could be
the real Sarah.
Uh. this is Poole's one big
book. right? Got him tenure.
but it doesn't read
like his earlier papers.
Listen to this language:
"As Anna Freud posited in 1936.
defence mechanisms
operate unconsciously
to protect the ego.
Repression. rejection.
sublimation. displacement.
Sigmund Freud swung at
these conditions with a hammer.
But Anna Freud believed
in time. layers. and patience.
She unpacked
these emotions with care
and painted them
with a watercolour brush."
- That's exactly what Sarah
said to us when we first met.
You think that's her research?
- And she gave it all to Poole?
- Romantic isn't it?
- Yeah. certainly is.
And that's how we break her.
Thanks for meeting me
here. Sarah.
How you feeling?
- I-I'm a little stunned.
I can't believe Garrett
said it was my idea
to lie about
his alibi.
Yeah. well.
we saw right through that.
- Well. I'm just glad
that you caught him.
Yeah.
But it's not over yet.
We still have to put him
behind bars and...
And there are aspects of both
Ivy and Kat's cases
that we just still don't
understand. so
hoping you can help.
- Well. I don't know Kat.
- Oh. that's okay.
Kat's murder was almost
exactly like Ivy's
and you know Ivy.
you know Garrett.
You're the expert here. not me.
I'm-I'm so curious about
your perspective.
- Hmm. I've already told you
everything I know.
- Facts. yeah.
But I'm looking for feelings.
And you were practically
inside their heads.
I mean. you were Ivy's therapist
and Garrett's muse.
- What do you mean
Garrett's muse?
- Oh. Sarah. I...
I read his book.
Those chapters on defence
mechanisms. impulsivity.
emotional dysregulation.
That was all you.
- No. no. no. no. no.
That wasn't all me.
We worked-we worked together.
- On your ideas?
- Well. I wanted to help him.
- Yeah. like you helped him
with his alibi?
It's okay.
I know it's not your fault.
I think that Garrett was able to
get away with these murders
because he manipulated
his victims. You included.
This guy was very careful.
- No. no. There's careful
and then there's controlling.
- Oh. what do you mean?
- Well. Ivy mentioned that
Garrett asked
to track her phone.
That's why she was so scared.
- Wow.
- He liked to lead
in relationships.
To have the upper hand.
- Well. was he like that
with you too?
In your relationship?
- Well. Garrett and I...
we're just friends.
Really?
Sarah. come on.
I can tell
when a woman is in love.
And Garrett knew how you felt
and he took advantage of that?
- What are you suggesting?
That I'm weak?
No. God. no.
No. I've. uh...
I've been there myself.
- Huh.
- My rookie year. I fell
absolutely head over heels
with a guy that I worked with.
I became obsessed.
I memorized his schedule.
I followed him around.
I would make excuses
to work together...
- Did he like you back?
- He liked my work.
He liked it so much that
sometimes he would claim it.
As his own.
- Hmm.
- Yeah. eventually he did. He
did want more than just my work.
- So he did like you back.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
But. uh. he didn't like me
enough to get serious
'cause. uh. turns out he was
married the entire time.
- Oh.
- And I wanted a kid.
I wanted a family.
- That's terrible.
At least Garrett isn't married.
- Well. no.
He is otherwise engaged.
He spends his time
on frivolous things.
but gives you
just enough to hang on.
Kind words. empty promises.
and all the while.
your time marches on.
your window is closing.
- I have always had feelings
for Garrett.
- Hmm.
- But he... He said that
we shouldn't cross the line
that we were colleagues.
- But he crosses the line
with his students.
- But that's none of
my business.
And I have-I have accepted
that we're just friends.
- No. friends don't steal
their friend's work.
Friends don't use their friends
to try to cover up their affairs
with students.
And friends don't blame
their friends for their crimes.
Or maybe they do.
See. I think you might be doing
exactly that to Garrett.
- What are you talking about?
- Sarah. how would you
define projection?
- It's when someone attributes
their own undesirable feelings.
thoughts. and behaviours
to somebody else.
- Okay. so when you suggested
that Ivy was Borderline
with a touch of Paranoid
Personality Disorder
and intense emotions.
and fear of abandonment.
impulsivity. delusions--
- I am not delusional.
Detective.
And I-I actually I've done
nothing but try to help you.
- Yeah. Well. you've been
very helpful.
Yeah. when you wanted me
to trust you and like you.
you told me everything
I wanted to hear.
But I've read your notes and
I've made some of my own
and I think all those things you
were saying about Ivy...
...you were really talking
about yourself.
- Huh.
- Sarah. stop.
- No. no. no. no. no. no.
I'm done here.
From the moment that I walked
into that office.
you've been trying
to manipulate me.
- And now you are trying
to turn the tables
with anger and contempt
and it's not gonna work.
- Was that your attempt
at empathizing in there?
At relating?
God. you are so
out of your depth.
You should be embarrassed.
- See. you're projecting again.
You've been carrying a torch for
that man for 10 years.
10 years of him
stealing your work.
tossing you scraps
while he screws his students.
And you know it's shameful
and you still can't stop.
- I don't need Garrett.
- No. you don't.
but you want him.
You want him fully and forever
and you know he wants you too.
He just needed a little nudge.
You know that one day
he's gonna wake up
and look at you and see
what is right in front of him.
What's been here all along.
You just needed those girls
to get out of the way.
They're baubles.
They're trinkets.
But you...
You are the real thing.
So you stabbed Kat
outside her house.
you tracked Ivy's phone
and you killed her.
- No. no. You have no proof.
- I know that you
threw away your key card.
And Ivy was smart.
She grabbed it. didn't she?
As she was dying?
'Cause in her last moments.
she wanted to leave a trace.
Someone. stop her.
please stop this monster--
- Ivy-Ivy was a child. okay?
An idiotic fool.
And she thought that
Garrett was gonna. what?
Leave his job and marry her?
I tried to play nice.
- How?
- I told her to leave.
I said leave town.
but she-she stuck around.
She didn't listen.
- Garrett didn't listen either?
- No! He never does.
I-I-I don't know
what I have to do!
- And that's why you threw him
under the bus.
To make him listen.
to make him yours.
Yes!
Yes because then. then it would
finally be me and him
and I would stand by him
and I would visit him
and-and when he got out of
prison he would know who...
He would know who
really loved him.
- I wonder if
he's gonna visit you.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Think I used more hammer
than I did watercolour.
Well.
whatever the tool.
we still painted our killer
into a corner.
- It's never easy to corner
another woman.